Finding Aid for Tailyour Family Papers
William L. Clements Library, University of Michigan
- John Tailyour (1743-1815)
  - Correspondence
    - Letters
      - Foulerton, George, 10 April 1804-29 May 1811, 13 items
      - Foulerton, John, 14 July 1793-20 July 1812, 77 items
      - Foulerton, Mary, 14 March 1810, 1 item
      - Fullertoun, John Carnegie, 18 July 1803-23 November 1805, 4 items
      - Foulerton, Mary Carnegie, 13 January 1806-22 June 1806, 11 items
      - Gadie, Theo, 13 September 1804, 1 item (Box 6)
      - Gallraith, A, 11 August 1793-18 May 1794, 3 items
      - Garden, Francis, 10 July 1800-October 04 1802, 5 items
      - Gardiner, Alex 5 September 1808, 1 item
      - Gerard, Gilbert, 3 October 1799-4 September 1811, 3 items
      - Gilchrist, Arch, 5 September 1801-7 October 1801, 2 items
      - Gillespie, David, 5 November 1806-25 September 1811, 3 items
      - Gillis, R & Co, 20 April 1800-10 May 1800, 3 items
      - Glennie, John, 30 April 1800, 1 item
      - Gordon, James Badenack, 18 September 1809, 1 item
      - Graham, William C., 20 June 1798, 1 item
      - Grahame, Arch, 6 June 1796-20 April 1797, 4 items
      - Grant, George, 15 May 1793, 1 item
      - Gray Wear and Gray, 3 February 1806-13 December 1806, 2 items
      - Thomas Gray lawsuit, 26 June 1809-18 June 1810, 4 items
      - Greenhill, Charles, 3 November 1800-21 November 1800, 2 items
      - Greig, John, 21 October 1802-22 March 1811, 5 items
      - Grunhill, Charles, 1 October 1794-18 November 1797, 8 items
      - Hamilton, Hugh, 14 September 1795, 1 item
      - Harris, Thomas, 10 April 1794, 1 item
      - Harrison, Joseph, 4 February 1794-26 September 1795, 5 items
      - Hayhurst, Poole & Felectcher, 11 April 1793, 1 item
      - Henry, Alex, 18 September 1806, 1 item
      - Hibbert & Hibbert, 7 January 1795-8 January 1796, 6 items
      - Hill, Dr. George, 24 June 1797-13 October 1806, 23 items
      - Hindy, Thomas and son, 1 June 1793-30 September 1793, 4 items
      - Hodgson, Edward, 3 February 1810, 1 item
      - Hodgson, John, 3 March 1794, 1 item
      - Holcombe, Thomas, 1 September 1794-20 December 1794, 3 items
      - Horn, Fredrick, 2 August 1805, 1 item
      - Hugham, Taylor/Ch. Clarke, 27 September 1806-16 April 1810, 3 items
      - Humfrey & Man, 28 September 1793, 1 item
      - Innes, Allan, 27 January 1802, 1 item
      - Innes, John, 19 May 1804-24 May 1804, 2 items
      - Jackson, George, 20 February 1798-24 April 1798, 2 items
      - Jameson, John, 20 June 1793-16 November 1793, 3 items
      - Jameson, William, 25 June 1800, 1 item
      - Jolly Lawsuit, 16 May 1784-24 October 1815, 30 items
      - Jones, James, 29 October 1792-2 October 1794, 14 items
      - Jones, Thomas, August 1796-23 December 1797, 3 items
      - Keith, Charles, 8 June 1804-28 September 1804, 2 items
      - Keith, George Skene, 24 May 1810, 1 item
      - Keith, John, 23 June 1806, 1 item
      - Kelso, William, 4 June 1810, 1 item
      - Key, Pat, 30 January 1796-29 April 1805, 5 items
      - Kidd, Alexander, 10 December 1805-21 April 1807, 11 items
      - King, Philip, 6 June 1792-15 March 1793, 2 items
      - Lamb, William, 23 July 1795-13 December 1806, 8 items
      - Learmonth, John & Co., 2 July 1808-21 October 1811, 2 items
      - Leckie, Alex, 20 October 1793-7 January 1794, 3 items
      - Leckie, George, 30 December 1793, 1 item
      - Leslie, James, 19 July 1806-14 October 1811, 13 items (Box 7)
      - Leyland, Thomas, 16 January 1794-11 March 1794, 5 items
      - Livingston, William, 28 March 1806, 1 item
      - Livright, David, 20 August 1794, 1 item
      - Low, Andrew & Alexander, 15 August 1795-21 April 1798, 3 items
      - Low, John, 3 April 1798-17 March 1812, 60 items
      - Luther, Francis, 24 December 1810, 1 item
      - Lyell, Charles, 12 December 1797-26 December 1797, 2 items
      - Lyon & Jobson, 10 June 1797, 1 item
      - Lyon, Paul, 30 October 1815, 1 item
      - MacKenzie, John, 10 July 1794-10 August 1809, 5 items
      - MacKenzie, Ken, 29 October 1808-27 January 1813, 35 items
      - MacLarty, Colin, 7 December 1800-25 December 1808, 4 items
      - Macleod, Alex, 7 July 1804-4 December 1804, 2 items
      - Marshall, Frank & Sons, 11 May 1811-24 May 1811, 3 items
      - Martin, Robert, 19 September 1796, 1 item
      - Maule, William, 18 August 1806-30 October 1806, 2 items
      - McCall, Arch, 16 January 1803-5 November 1811, 46 items
      - McCall, Christina, 13 January 1809-15 February 1813, 15 items (Box 8)
      - McCall, Dick & Co., 6 March 1802-1 September 1803, 4 items
      - McCall, George, 23 March 1792-12 July 1805, 224
      - McCall, George, 25 September 1805-17 January 1810, 37 (Box 9)
      - McCall, George, Jr., 30 October 1798-1 May 1813, 59 items
      - McCall, James, 15 January 1800-5 September 1811, 30 items
      - McCall, John, 13 August 1792-11 March 1804, 113
      - McCall, John, 26 March 1804-3 March 1809, 63 (Box 10)
      - McCall, Mary, 19 June 1809-15 October 1811, 4 items
      - McCall, Robert, 25 March 1809, 1 item
      - McCall, Samuel, 29 September 1793-19 September 1806, 34 items
      - McCall, Samuel, Jr., 11 September 1793-3 November 1811, 103 items
      - McNair, Robert, 17 April 1804, 1 item (Box 11)
      - Mengies, John, 22 September 1800-20 October 1809, 7 items
      - Middlewood, JW, 26 February 1795, 1 item
      - Miles, Philip John, 5 February 1793-21 February 1794, 9 items
      - Miles, William, 3 September 1792-23 June 1800, 13 items
      - Miles, William & Son, 24 September 1794-25 October 1799, 28 items
      - Miles, William & Son (signed by James Room), 21 March 1793-5 September 1796, 9 items
      - Mill, James, 1 February 1800-19 February 1800, 2 items
      - Mill, John, 19 October 1811, 1 item
      - Mill, Louis, 17 November 1794, 1 item
      - Milm, Robert, 30 December 1800, 1 item
      - Milne, John, 18 March 1810, 1 item
      - Monro, Charles, 8 December 1804-28 March 1808, 4 items
      - Lord Newton, 13 April 1811, 1 item
      - Noble, James, 9 October 1793-21 May 1795, 8 items
      - Oglivy, Wm, 16 December 1793, 1 item
      - Orr, John, 14 October 1792-13 July 1809, 5 items
      - Orr, Patrick, 4 April 1798-10 September 1798, 3 items
      - Oswald, Alexander, 24 August 1795, 1 item
      - Oswald, George, 19 September 1795-28 June 1808, 17 items
      - Paten, James, 20 January 1796-20 February 1796, 2 items
      - Paterson, Dundas, 8 March 1803, 1 item
      - Paterson, John, 4 January 1793, 1 item
      - Paterson, William, 25 October 1797, 1 item
      - Peter, John, 28 November 1809-2 January 1810, 3 items
      - Peters, Alexander, 5 August 1808, 1 item
      - Prtheroe & Claxton, 10 April 1793, 1 item
      - Rainford, James, 16 May 1793-16 May 1794, 2 items
      - Ramsay, Sir Alex, 23 January 1798-23 September 1810, 5 items
      - Ranken, John, 29 March 1809-15 December 1810, 2 items
      - Ratlif, Joseph, 24 March 1794, 1 item
      - Rawlinson, William, 22 August 1793, 1 item
      - Reid, David, 13 December 1793, 1 item
      - Renny, Hercules, 22 December 1805-1 March 1808, 3 items
      - Renny, James, 5 October 1792-18 September 1797, 14 items
      - Renny, Patrick, 4 March 1796, 1 item
      - Renny, Thomas, 25 February 1793-28 December 1805, 247 (Box 12)
      - Renny, Thomas, 1 January 1806-1 February 1809, 74 (Box 13)
      - Renwick, Ann, 13 July 1807, 1 items
      - Renwick, John, 20 May 1803-22 August 1811, 31 items
      - Ritchie, Charles, 11 December 1799-11 February 1803, 7 items
      - Ritchie, H, 7 May 1811, 1 item
      - Robertson, George, 27 June 1806, 1 item
      - Rogers, James, 4 February 1793, 1 item
      - Ross, H. Irvine, 30 December 1808, 1 item
      - Russell, Francis, 28 May 1797-2 February 1806, 4 items
      - Sargent, Chambers & Co., 9 May 1793-20 September 1794, 4 items
      - Scott, David, 26 July 1795, 1 item
      - Scott, George Robertson, 3 November 1802-22 March 1811, 7 items
      - Scott, John, 28 May 1793-9 July 1811, 22 items
      - Scott, John & Will, 17 March 1795, 1 item
      - Selkrig, Charles, 25 June 1802-28 September 1802, 3 items
      - Shaw, Campbell & Kirkpatrick, 20 August 1793, 1 item
      - Shaw, John George, 11 April 1793-1 June 1793, 4 items
      - Simpson, Henry, 23 November 1809-25 October 1811, 3 items
      - Sims, William, 23 November 1804-27 November 1804, 2 items
      - Sinclair, William, 9 May 1794-20 May 1794, 2 items
      - Skelton, Thomas, 19 February 1794, 1 item
      - Skene, George, 7 February 1796-28 November 1805, 3 items
      - Smart, Will, 31 January 1807, 1 item
      - Smith, Alex, 23 October 1803, 1 item
      - Smith, George, 12 January 1794-12 January 1795, 3 items
      - Smith, James, 2 May 1800, 1 item
      - Smith, William, 16 January 1806-22 December 1806, 2 items
      - Souter, James, 20 November 1795, 1 item
      - Souther, Francis, 7 July 1807, 1 item
      - Spiers, Peter, 22 February 1801-4 March 1802, 4 items
      - Spottiswood, John, 21 December 1799-25 February 1800, 3 items
      - Stevenson, Robert, 6 February 1811-17 November 1811, 8 items
      - Stewart, John, 10 May 1793-31 March 1803, 7 items
      - Stewart, Rob, 24 July 1800-29 November 1800, 2 items
      - Stirling, James, 6 February 1793-5 April 1793, 3 items (Box 14)
      - Strachan, Alex, 28 January 1800-15 April 1807, 2 items
      - Strachan, James, 12 November 1798, 1 item
      - Strachan, Thomas Renny, 14 September 1798-22 October 1811, 46 items
      - Stuart, John, 27 January 1805-10 January 1810, 4 items
      - Sutherland, John & William, 4 November 1795-8 August 1803, 12 items
      - Tailyour, Alexander Renny, 10 October 1806-2 December 1811, 24 items
      - Tailyour, Hercules, 20 February 1783-22 October 1811, 132 items
      - Tailyour, Jean, 19 March 1793-13 February 1794, 30 items (Box 15)
      - Tailyour, Robert, 16 February 1743, 1 item; Partnership agreement with John Parminter
      - Tarleton & Rigg, 28 December 1793-5 June 1794, 7 items
      - Taylor & Hughan, 7 June 1806-5 November 1810, 5 items
      - Taylor, Ballantine & Fairlie, 16 September 1792-20 May 1798, 100 items
      - Taylor, Hughan & Co., 27 February 1806-10 July 1811, 8 items
      - Taylor, Hughan & Renny, 28 November 1798-23 May 1805, 20 items
      - Taylor, James, 16 December 1801-21 October 1810, 16 items
      - Taylor, John, 22 July 1809-24 September 1811, 15 items; Son of John Tailyour
      - Taylor, Mary, 16 December 1792-4 October 1811, 5 items
      - Taylor, Robert, 20 October 1784-27 May 1804, 235 items (Box 16)
      - Taylor, Robert, 12 June 1804-17 March 1813, 180 items (Box 17)
      - Taylor, Robert, 28 November 1806, 1 item; Son of John Tailyour
      - Taylor, Robert, 5 January 1808-11 July 1811, 3 items; Son of Robert Taylor
      - Taylor, Simon, 20 May 1791-23 May 1811, 107 items
      - Taylor, Simon, 27 April 1802-13 April 1804, 9 items; Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 18)
      - Taylor, Simon R.B., 22 November 1798-6 June 1801, 8 items
      - Wade, Mrs. D.W., 12 December 1792-22 November 1795, 3 items
      - Walker, Alex, 5 October 1796-19 September 1801, 2 items
      - Walker, George, 16 July 1807-21 November 1811, 41 items
      - Walker, James, 26 December 1807-17 April 1810, 3 items
      - Walker, Thompson & Co., 24 February 1808-8 April 1808, 3 items
      - Walker, Will, 10 September 1803-15 May 1804, 2 items
      - Wallace, John, 24 May 1794, 1 item
      - Wallis, Henry, 30 April 1798, 1 item
      - Warwick, Anthony, 2 September 1793-19 March 1794, 2 items
      - Webster, James, 17 November 1796, 1 item
      - White, Thomas, Jr., 20 November 1798-12 June 1799, 2 items
      - Williamson, William, 24 July 1795, 1 item
      - Wilson, James, 15 December 1804, 1 item
      - Wood, James, 30 November 1809-30 June 1810, 4 items
      - Yuille, Thomas, 27 June 1800-7 July 1800, 2 items
      - Misc. Correspondence, 26 August 1786-12 December 1800, 5 items; Authors unknown
    - Letterbooks
      The four letterbooks that have survived contain 1,116 retained copies of Tailyour's letters. His early letter books (1781-1785) detail his initial struggles in America, when he first tried his hand at general trade, and later attempted to provide supplies for British prisoners-of-war after the American Revolution. Both attempts failed, and by 1782, he started thinking about moving to Jamaica to work with his cousin Simon Taylor. During this time, Tailyour kept in touch with his British contacts, including George McCall, the Andersons, and his brother Hercules, whom he hoped to recruit for the American trade.
      John Tailyour started his career in Kingston, Jamaica, as a trader in dry goods and sundry stores, but soon added the purchase and sale of slaves to his business. Many of his letters after 1783 focus on the condition of the slave trade and the threat from abolitionists in England. Tailyour styled himself as an expert slave trader, able to sell entire ships of slaves quickly. Much of his correspondence about the trade focuses on the kinds of issues that affected its viability, including the health of the slaves, the health of the markets, the age and sex of the slaves, and the locations of sale.
      Tailyour wrote many letters about the abolitionist threat as well, and the damage he anticipated from abolition. Contrary to some accounts, Tailyour's reports on the slave trade indicate that it was robust at the end of the eighteenth century. Though he foresaw a potentially large loss of business if the trade were outlawed, Tailyour did not reflect much on the social effects of this, but he did note in 1788 that "from all the best information I ever had, it clearly appears Slaves live better by far in the West Indies than in Africa, & from my own observations I can say they in general live better than the Poor of Scotland, Ireland & probably England."
      Toward the end of his life, Tailyour wrote more directly about issues concerning his health, his estate in Scotland, and the business news from his correspondents.
      - Tailyour, John Letterbook, 1781-1785 (Volume 1)
        - 1781, 11 items
        - 1782, 35 items
        - 1783, 47 items
        - 1784, 22 items
        - 1785, 28 items
      - Tailyour, John Letterbook, 1788-1789 (Volume 2)
        - 1788, 139 items
        - 1789, 207 items
      - Tailyour, John Letterbook, 1790-1792 (Volume 3)
        - 1790, 184 items
        - 1791, 206 items
        - 1792, 194 items
      - Tailyour, John Letterbook, 1804-1810 (Volume 4)
        - 1804, 1 item
        - 1805, 8 items
        - 1806, 5 items
        - 1807, 3 items
        - 1808, 5 items
        - 1809, 15 items
        - 1810, 6 items
  - Business papers
    John Tailyour's business papers comprise 32 letters and his five account books. The business papers relate to his estates in Scotland, particularly Kirktonhill. Several letters between Tailyour and his good friends Thomas Renny and Peter Ballantine contain accounts and vouchers. Tailyour wrote two letters to John Baveridge. Also included are several bonds procured in Scotland and additional contracts. For accounts regarding his estate, consult series II and III.
    Tailyour's account books are divided between his pre- and post-1792 finances. Those prior to 1792 focus on his Kingston estate and his accounts regarding trade and personal expenses. Those after 1792 relate to his Scottish estates, particularly Kirktonhill and Craigo. His account journal for Kirktonhill includes personal, estate, and expense accounts, as well as several bills, receipts, and accounting balances.
    - Documents
      - John Tailyour & T. Renny Accounts, 20 June 1793-1 May 1799, 3 items (Box 18)
      - John Tailyour & T. Renny Vouchers, 1806-27 December 1806, 16 items
      - John Tailyour & P. Ballantine Accounts, July 1797, 1 item
      - John Baveridge Accounts, 1797-1801, 2 items
      - Scotland Bonds, 14 June 1798-13 December 1806, 7 items
      - Contracts, 1811 2 November 1808-2 December 1811, 3 items
    - Account Books
      - John Tailyour Account Journal, 1789 (Volume 5)
      - John Tailyour Account Journal, 1790 (Volume 6)
      - John Tailyour Account Journal, 1798-1805, part 1 (Volume 7)
      - John Tailyour Account Journal, 1798-1805, part 2 (Volume 8)
      - John Tailyour Account Journal, Kirktonhill, 1805-1813 (Volume 9)
      - John Tailyour Account Journal, 1806-1816 (Volume 10)
- Tailyour Estate (Post-1815)
  - Correspondence
    The correspondence for the Tailyour estate after 1815 almost entirely concerns estate accounts, primarily regarding division and management issues immediately after Tailyour’s death in 1815. Mid-nineteenth century accounts also focus on the Tailyour family estate. Finally, a small collection of letters from Simon Taylor to his parents in the 1860s concern his travels abroad.
    - John Tailyour Estate Correspondence, 16 March 1816-20 November 1819, 138 items (Box 19)
    - Jackson, John, 29 May 1820, 1 item
  - Business Papers
    The collection's business papers after 1815 contain 1716 individual items, which divide into six large sections: Tailyour family estate accounts from 1823-36; the expense accounts from 1838-43; accounts of the family's farm from 1824-27; accounts paid between 1833-39; the salmon fishing records from 1836-47; and the vouchers and factory accounts for the family's crop between 1816-1818. Additional items include a number of receipts from Robert Taylor and some accounting letters to Brand and Burnett. Most of these accounts are for the Kirktonhill and Craigo estates, and lands rented out. The salmon fishing accounts are quite extensive, detailing the family's finances in the profitable salmon industry of northeast Scotland.Ten account books concern the post-1815 estate. These provide estate and expense accounts for the Tailyour assets. The Accounts and Legal Forms book from 1820-1821 includes a number of legal opinions and expositions on accounts and cases during this period. The rent book of 1833-36 reports personal and estate finances for the land on the family's Marykirk and Garrock estates, which were located just outside the primary Kirktonhill estate. Robert Taylor's account journal centers on his mercantile accounts in Edinburgh, and also includes a waste book. Finally, Simon Taylor's account book contains his Edinburgh merchant records.
    - Documents
      - Accounts, Robert Taylor & John Brand, 10 June 1815-2 March 1826, 31 items
      - Accounts, Robert Taylor, Robert Burness & John Grieg, November 1823-16 July 1847, 18 items
      - Accounts, Robert Taylor & Brand Burnett, 25 February 1840-6 July 1858, 12 items
      - Accounts, Robert Taylor & James Birnie, 12 October 1841, 1 item
      - Accounts, Robert Taylor & W & J Cook, 1 October 1842-11 November1844, 6 items
      - Accounts, Estate Accounts, 27 June 1823-23 January 1824, 11 items
      - Accounts, Estate Accounts, 11 February 1824-19 June 1824, 21 items
      - Accounts, Estate Accounts, 30 July 1825-17 December 1825, 13 items
      - Accounts, Estate Accounts, 20 July 1825-17 June 1826, 13 items
      - Accounts, Estate Accounts, 7 March 1827-23 June 1827, 10 items
      - Accounts, Estate Accounts, March 1827-21 June 1828, 25 items
      - Accounts, Estate Accounts, 15 July 1829-19 June 1830, 11 items
      - Accounts, Estate Accounts, 15 July 1832-22 June 1833, 22 items
      - Accounts, Estate Accounts, 20 September 1833-21 June 1834, 24 items
      - Accounts, Estate Accounts, 8 July 1834-7 February 1835, 19 items (Box 20)
      - Accounts, Estate Accounts, 8 June 1835-20 June 1835, 4 items
      - Accounts, Expense Accounts, 20 June 1835-16 February 1836, 59 items
      - Accounts, Estate Accounts, 23 October 1835-28 January 1836, 14 items
      - Accounts, Estate Accounts, 12 February 1836-18 June 1836, 11 items
      - Accounts, Expense Accounts, 1 January 1838-7 June 1838, 70 items
      - Accounts, Expense Accounts, 22 March 1838-29 June 1839, 167 items
      - Accounts, Expense Accounts, 29 January 1841-27 January 1842, 92 items
      - Accounts, Expense Accounts, 31 January 1842-14 December 1843, 112 items (Box 21)
      - Accounts, Farm Accounts, 24 May 1824-24 November 1824, 32 items
      - Accounts, Farm Accounts, 26 November 1824-27 May 1825, 39 items
      - Accounts, Farm Accounts, 30 May 1825-2 December 1825, 48 items
      - Accounts, Farm Accounts, 6 December 1825-27 May 1826, 24 items
      - Accounts, Farm Accounts, 19 November 1826-2 June 1827, 34 items
      - Accounts, Farm Accounts, 14 June 1827-18 December 1827, 41 items
      - Accounts Paid, 8 May 1833-10 June 1835, 55 items
      - Accounts Paid, 24 July 1835-9 December 1836, 53 items
      - Accounts Paid (by Wm. Kurk), 17 July 1838-18 June 1839, 9 items
      - Accounts Paid, 2 June 1838-3 January 1840, 53 items
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 2 December 1835-10 December 1836, 28 items (Box 22)
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 14 December 1836-7 March 1838, 20 items
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 1837, 1 memo book
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, January 1838-6 October 1838, 35 items
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 1838, 1 memo book
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 8 October 1838-28 November 1839, 20 items
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, February 1839, 1 memo book
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 4 January 1840-28 December 1840, 17 items
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 1840, 1 memo book
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 8 January 1841-8 October 1841, 18 items
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 1841, 1 memo book; Kept by William Scott at Marykirk.
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 9 December 1841-30 December 1842, 26 items
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 1842, 1 memo book
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 27 December 1842-3 November 1843, 15 items
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 1843, 1 memo book
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 12 December 1843-16 January 1845, 18 items
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 1844, 1 memo book
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 17 December 1844-9 January 1846, 14 items
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 1845, 1 memo book
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 1846, 1 memo book
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 16 January 1846-2 December 1846, 13 items
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 7 December 1846-31 December 1847, 19 items
      - Accounts, Salmon Fishing, 1847, 1 memo book
      - Accounts, Brand & Burnett, 1834-1836, 14 items
      - Receipts, Robert Taylor, 18 May 1816-7 September 1822, 101 items
      - Vouchers & Factory Accounts, 12 April 1808-18 July 1817, 90 items; 1816 crop. (Box 23)
      - Vouchers & Factory Accounts, 1809-14 November 1819, 108 items; 1817 crop.
      - Vouchers & Factory Accounts, 1818-1819, 23 items; 1818 crop.
    - Account Books
      - Accounts and Legal Forms, 1820-1821 (Volume 11)
      - Account Journal: Rent Book, 1833-1836 (Volume 12)
      - Simon Taylor Account Journal, 1812 (Volume 13)
      - Robert Taylor, Account Journal, 1812 (Volume 14)
      - Robert Taylor, Account Journal, 1821 (Volume 15)
      - George Taylor, Account Journal & Cash Book, 1815, 1821
      - George Taylor, Account Journal & Waste Book, 1820
      - George Taylor, Account Journal, 1821
      - George Taylor, Account Journal, Invoices & Sales, 1821
      - Robert Taylor, Account Journal with misc. papers, 1834-1849 (Volume 16)
  - Hunting Papers
    The hunting papers catalogue the various adventures and important details of the Tailyour family hunting expeditions. The journals include descriptions of the locations of the hunts, detailed stories of the hunts themselves, and ratings of performance after each event. The lists of hunting dogs provide not only the name, but also the pedigree and some description of the dogs used by the Tailyour family for their regular foxhunts.
    - Hunting Journal, 1818, 1827 (Box 23)